Scott E. Roberts

Email: s.e.roberts0@gmail.com | Personal Website: https://scotteroberts.github.io
GitHub: https://www.github.com/ScotteRoberts | LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/scott-e-roberts

OBJECTIVE

Currently seeking an entry-level Software Engineer / Software Developer position in hopes of contributing to long-lasting, secure solutions that improve the lives of users. Three years of experience in object-oriented programming. Acquired skills developing secure, extensible, and scalable solutions while following the Agile software design principles using Scrum.

SKILLS

Operating Systems: MacOS, iOS, Windows 10, Windows 7
Languages: C#, Java, SQL, ES6, Python, C++

Environments: Visual Studio, Visual Studio Code, Eclipse, Xcode, NetBeans, Anaconda Spyder

Frameworks: .NET, ASP.NET, Entity Framework, Vue.js, Bulma

Tools: GitHub, Terminal, PowerShell, Google Suite, Trello, Slack, Axosoft, GitKraken

PROJECTS

Team Lead | Web Application | Software Engineering Senior Project

Sep. 2017 – May 2018

- Led a team of 6 developers using Scrum while following the Agile methodology and implemented a deployable single page application (SPA) that collected and stored internet articles via web crawling to guarantee a safe environment for users to learn at their leisure
- Integrated with a mock Single Sign On service to simplify user authentication and promote awareness of other company applications
- Improved team velocity by at least 15% each sprint by enforcing daily standups using Google Suite

Developer | Desktop Application | Operating System Project

Sep. 2017 – Dec. 2017

 Implemented a multi-process and multi-threaded application using shared memory to coordinate a search and destroy algorithm which resulted in a 50% - 75% destroy rate

Developer | Desktop Application | Security Project

Sep. 2017 – Dec. 2017

- Implemented a Ransomware application with a Python cryptography library to encrypt files using AES-CBC, SHA-256, and RSA
- Configured an SSL-protected **EC2** instance to store the Ransomware keys

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineering Intern | Enterprise Portfolio Software

May 2017 – Aug. 2017

 Communicated internationally via Skype with a software engineer to improve the UI/UX for a proprietary project management web application

Director | California Junior Lifeguard Programs Inc.

Jun. 2016 – Aug. 2017

- Led 60-100 children (6 15 years old) and 10-15 Instructors during an all-day summer camp by enforcing proper safety protocols and creating efficient daily agendas for multiple age groups which resulted in a safer, organized camp environment
- Communicated directly with parents on camp costs, upgrade fees, and children's behavior to ensure customer satisfaction and inclusion into camp activities
- Maintained an average 50% return rate of participants by including old activities for mastery
 of skills and designing new, engaging activities to preserve camp interest
- Performed responsibilities of an Instructor when the program was short-staffed

Instructor | California Junior Lifeguard Programs Inc.

Jun. 2011 – Aug. 2015

- Reduced potential injuries by identifying potential victims and hazards on land and water and responded to life-threatening situations through prepared Emergency Action Plans
- Educated children in teamwork, physical fitness, lifesaving skills, and oceanography through
 physical activities and group lectures which improved participants respectfulness toward
 leadership and peers and encouraged community awareness
- Collaborated with other Instructors to plan fun activities with limited resources in order to efficiently lead participants

Mathematics Tutor | Self-Employed

- Provided a patient, friendly environment for frustrated high school and college students to learn and practice their homework and test problems
- Helped students with assignments in Algebra, Geometry, Trigonometry, Pre-Calculus, and Calculus and ensured that each client improved by at least one letter grade

Aug. 2011 – May 2015

ACTIVITIES

Game Programmer/Designer | CSULB Video Game Development Association, Technical Team

Aug. 2015 – May 2016

- Scrummed with the design/tech/art team making scripted puzzles
- Collaborated in development jams to solidify design concepts

Informative Public Speaker | OCC Speech and Debate Team

Jan. 2014 – Jan. 2015

Gold medal winner for Novice Informative Speaking

Tutor | Casa Youth Shelter

Oct. 2012 – Apr. 2013

• Contributed over 20 hours of community service to assist elementary and middle school students develop their math and English skills during an afterschool care program

Assistant Instructor | California Junior Lifeguard Programs Inc.

May 2009 – May 2011

- Contributed over 400 hours of community service learning how to provide quality teaching experiences to children (age 8 13)
- Presented multiple discussions on stingray species, dangers, and presence in local Orange County beaches to educate participants on creating emergency plans for unusual incidents
- Assisted with menial, but necessary tasks such as cleaning equipment, setting up base camp, setting up swim areas, and judging group activities which helped Instructors perform tasks such as group management and teaching

EDUCATION

California State University, Long Beach | Long Beach, CA Bachelor of Science in Computer Science | Cumulative GPA: 3.8 Graduated: May 2018

Orange Coast College | Costa Mesa, CA Completed general education courses for transfer Sep. 2013 – Dec. 2015